Guide to the Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Samuel and Bella Spewack Papers,
ca.1920-1980
Spewack, Samuel and Bella.
72 linear ft (ca.75,000 items in 150 boxes).
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
4079732
Biographical Note
Samuel Spewack, 1899-1971 (Columbia College B.A., 1919) and Bella Cohen Spewack, 1899 1990, were authors of Broadway plays and musicals, novels, short stories, and articles. They were also foreign correspondents for Europe and Russia for the New York World, 1919-1926, and the New York Herald Tribune, 1922-1926, respectively.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, manuscripts, playscripts, screenplays, diaries, documents, contracts, financial records, photographs, phonograph records, motion pictures, playbills, posters, sheet music, cartoons, art work, memorabilia, scrapbooks, and printed materials.. The collection consists chiefly of correspondence and production files relating to the creation, production, and performance of their works for stage, screen, radio, and television, such as Leave It To Me and Kiss Me Kate (with music by Cole Porter), Boy Meets Girl, and My Three Angels. Correspondence (with twentieth century authors, playwrights, musicians, political figures, and actors) includes: George Abbott, Jean Arthur, Bennett Cerf, Katharine Cornell, Jo Davidson, George and Ira Gershwin, Alec Guinness, W. Averell Harriman, Lilli Lehmann, Mary Martin, Laurence Olivier, Mary Pickford, Cole Porter, Regina Resnick, Eleanor Roosevelt, Robert E. Sherwood, Lincoln Steffens, Kurt Weill, Rebecca West, and Thornton Wilder. There is also correspondence concerning Bella Spewack's work with the New York Girls' Scholarship, UNRA, and the Sports Cente of Israel. In addition to the production files, there are manuscripts and typescript drafts for novels, short stories, and articles by the Spewacks.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 23 series:
Series I: Cataloged Cprrespondence
Series II: Cataloged Manuscripts and Documents
Series III: Cataloged Photographs
Series IV: Cataloged Art
Series V: Arranged Art
Series VI: Personal Correspondence
Series VII: Friends
Series VIII: General Correspondence
Series IX: Productions
Series X: Short Stories and Articles
Series XI: Personal Information
Series XII: Bella and Sam Together
Series XIII: Financial Information
Series XIV: Photographs
Series XV: Memorabilia
Series XVI: Printed Material
Series XVII: Audio-Visual Material
Series XVIII: Oversize Material
Series XIX: Scrapbooks
Series XX: Record Albums
Series XXI: Films
Series XXII: Flat Boxes
Series XXIII: Posters
Subjects
New York Girls' Scholarship.; Sports Center of Israel.; United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration.; Abbott, George, 1887-1995.; Acosta, Mercedes de, 1893-1968.; Adams, Edie, 1912-; Aherne, Brian.; Albert, Eddie.; Andrews, Julie.; Arthur, Jean, 1905-1991.; Atkinson, Brooks, 1894-1984.; Aumont, Jean Pierre.; Baird, Bil, 1904-1987.; Baird, Cora Burlar.; Baker, Russell, 1925-; Baum, Vicki, 1888-1960.; Beaumont, Hugh, 1909-1982.; Bedford, Brian, 1935-; Belasco, David, 1853-1931.; Berg, Gertrude, 1899-1966.; Bergman, Ingrid, 1915-1982.; Bernstein, Aline, 1881-1955.; Bikel, Theodore.; Bing, Rudolf, 1902-1997.; Blackmer, Sidney, 1895-1973.; Blasco Ibáñez, Vicente, 1867-1928.; Blatas, Arbit.; Bonnet, Henri, 1888-1978.; Booth, Shirley, 1907-; Boyer, Charles, 1899-1978.; Brook, Peter.; Brooks, Van Wyck, 1886-1963.; Broun, Heywood, 1888-1939.; Brown, John Mason, 1900-1969.; Brown, Vanessa, 1928-; Calhern, Louis, 1895-1956.; Carmer, Carl Lamson, 1893-1976.; Cerf, Bennett, 1898-1971.; Champion, Gower, 1919-1980.; Channing, Carol.; Clavé, Antoni, 1913-2005.; Clooney, Rosemary.; Clurman, Harold, 1901-; Coca, Imogene.; Cohen, Benjamin V.; Cohen, Harriet.; Colbert, Claudette.; Collier, Constance, 1878-1955.; Connelly, Marc, 1890-1980.; Cooper, Diana, 1892-1986.; Cornell, Katharine, 1893-1974.; Craven, Frank, 1875-1945.; Crawford, Cheryl, 1902-1986.; Crist, Judith.; Cronkite, Walter.; Cronyn, Hume.; Crowther, Bosley.; Cukor, George, 1899-1983.; Dalrymple, Jean.; Dassin, Jules, 1911-2008.; Davidson, Florence Edenshaw, 1896-1993.; Davidson, Jo, 1883-1952.; Day, Dorothy, 1897-1980.; Douglas, Melvyn.; Drake, Alfred, 1914-1992.; Duke, Vernon, 1914-; Eldridge, Florence.; Enters, Angna, 1907-1989.; Erdman, Dick, 1925-; Evans, Maurice, 1901-1989.; Ewell, Tom, 1909-1994.; Fadiman, Clifton, 1904-1999.; Ferrer, Jʹose, 1912-; Flon, Suzanne, 1918-; Freedley, George, 1904-; Freud, Anna, 1895-1982.; Gard, Alex.; Garson, Greer, 1904-1996.; Gassner, John Waldhorn, 1903-; Geddes, Norman Bel, 1893-1958.; Gershwin, George, 1898-1937.; Gershwin, Ira, 1896-1983.; Gielgud, John, 1904-2000.; Gielgud, Val Henry, 1900-; Gilmore, Margalo, 1897-; Gingold, Hermione, 1897-; Glenn, John, 1921-; Glenville, Peter, 1913-; Goddard, Paulette, 1911-1990.; Goldwyn, Samuel, 1882-1974.; Gould, Morton, 1913-1996.; Grimes, Tammy.; Graham, Katharine, 1917-2001.; Guinness, Alec, 1914-2000.; Guthrie, Tyrone, Sir, 1900-1971.; Hagen, Uta, 1919-2004.; Hammerstein, Oscar, 1895-1960.; Harriman, W. Averell (William Averell), 1891-1986.; Harris, Jed.; Harris, Julie.; Harris, Rosemary, 1930-; Harris, Sam Hyde, 1889-1977.; Hart, Lorenz, 1895-1943.; Hart, Moss, 1904-1961.; Hartl, Léon, 1889-; Hassam, Childe, 1859-1935.; Hayes, Helen, 1900-1993.; Helburn, Thresa.; Hellman, Lillian, 1905-1984.; Helpmann, Robert, Sir, 1909-1986.; Henri, Robert, 1865-1929.; Hepburn, Katharine, 1907-2003.; Hirsch, Joseph, 1910-1981.; Hirschfeld, Al.; Holden, William, 1918-1981.; Hope, Constance, 1908-1977.; Hornblow, Arthur, 1893-1976.; Hull, Josephine, 1877-1957.; Hurok, Sol, 1888-1974.; Ives, Burl, 1909-1995.; Jones, Barry, 1893-1981.; Kanin, Garson, 1912-1999.; Karloff, Boris, 1887-1969.; Kaufman, George S. (George Simon), 1889-1961.; Keller, Helen, 1880-1968.; Kelly, Gene, 1912-1996.; Kilty, Jerome.; King, Alan, 1927-2004.; King, Alexander, 1900-1965.; Kirk, Lisa.; Kirkwood, James, 1930-1989.; Klopfer, Donald Simon, 1902-; Kravchenko, Alekseĭ Ilʹich, 1889-1940.; L'Anglais, Pascal.; Lawrence, Gertrude.; Lazar, Irving Paul.; Lederer, Charles, 1910-1976.; Lehmann, Lilli, 1848-1929.; Leigh, Vivien, 1913-1967.; Leighton, Margaret, 1922-1976.; Lewis, Mary, 1897-1941.; Loesser, Frank, 1910-1969.; Logan, Joshua.; Lombardo, Guy, 1902-1977.; Luhan, Mabel Dodge, 1879-1962.; Lumet, Sidney, 1924-; Lunt, Alfred.; Lyons, Leonard, 1906-1976.; McCarey, Leo.; MacMahon, Aline, 1899-1991.; Mankiewicz, Herman J. (Herman Jacob), 1897-1953.; Mantle, Burns, 1873-1948.; Markova, Alicia, 1910-; Martin, Mary, 1913-1990.; Marx, Zeppo, 1901-1979.; Masaryk, Jan, 1886-1948.; Matorin, Mikhail Vladimirovich, 1901-; Mellett, Lowell, 1884-1960.; Messel, Oliver, 1904-1978.; Middleton, George, 1880-1967.; Moffo, Anna.; Montalbán, Ricardo.; Montand, Yves, 1921-1991.; Moore, Dudley, 1935-2002.; Moore, Victor.; Morison, Patricia, 1915-; Murrow, Edward R.; Nesbitt, Cathleen, 1888-1982.; Newmar, Julie, 1930-; Nissen, Greta, 1906-; Norton, Elliot, 1903-; Nugent, Elliott, 1899-1980.; O'Brien, Edward Joseph Harrington, 1890-1941.; O'Casey, Sean, 1880-1964.; Olivier, Laurence, 1907-1989.; Page, Geraldine.; Palmer, Lilli, 1914-1986.; Parker, Dorothy, 1893-1967.; Patterson, Elizabeth, 1875-1966.; Pavlov, Ivan Nikolaevich, 1872-1951.; Pickford, Mary, 1892-1979.; Picon, Molly.; Porter, Cole, 1891-1964.; Powell, Dick, 1904-1963.; Pusey, James Carver.; Reinhardt, Max, 1873-1943.; Reinking, Ann.; Resnik, Regina, 1922-; Rice, Elmer, 1892-1967.; Richardson, Ralph, Sir, 1902-1983.; Richardson, Tony, 1928-; Ritchard, Cyril, 1897-1977.; Robertson Justice, James, 1907-1975.; Robinson, Edward G., 1893-1973.; Robson, Flora, 1902-1984.; Rodgers, Richard, 1902-1979.; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962.; Rosay, Françoise.; Rutland, Violet Lindsay Manners, Duchess of, d1937.; Salmi, Albert, 1928-; Schary, Dore.; Schildkraut, Joseph, 1895-1964.; Schulz, Charles M. (Charles Monroe), 1922-2000.; Schwartz, Arthur, 1900-1984.; Sellers, Peter, 1925-1980.; Selznick, Irene Mayer, 1907-1990.; Shaffer, Peter, 1926-; Shaw, Bernard, 1856-1950.; Sherwood, Robert E. (Robert Emmet), 1896-1955.; Shumlin, Herman, 1898-; Simonson, Lee, 1888-; Slezak, Walter, 1902-1983.; Sotomayor, Antonio, 1904-; Spewack, Bella Cohen, 1899-1990.; Spewack, Samuel, 1899-1971.; Steffens, Lincoln, 1866-1936.; Stokes, Rose Pastor, 1879-1933.; Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971.; Stromberg, Hunt, 1894-1968.; Styne, Jule, 1905-1994.; Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972.; Villa-Lobos, Heitor.; Weill, Kurt, 1900-1950.; West, Rebecca, 1892-1983.; Wilder, Thornton, 1897-1975.; Willkie, Wendell L. (Wendell Lewis), 1892-1944.; Spewack, Samuel, 1899-1971.; Spewack, Bella Cohen, 1899-1990.; Drama--20th century.; Dramatists, American--20th century.; Music--United States.; Theater--United States.; Crayon drawings.; Diaries.; Diplomas.; Drafts (literary).; Drawings.; Engravings.; Fiction.; Financial records.; Financial statements.; First drafts.; Greeting cards.; Insurance.; Interviews.; Legal documents.; Lists.; Manuscripts (literary).; Memorabilia.; Memorandums.; Menus.; Motion pictures.; Negatives.; Notebooks.; Notes.; Novels.; Obituaries.; Pamphlets.; Passports.; Pastel drawings.; Pen works.; Pencil works.; Phonograph records.; Photographs.; Plaques.; Playbills.; Portraits.; Postcards.; Posters.; Powers of attorney.; Press releases.; Printing plates.; Proofs.; Receipts.; Reports.; Reviews.; Schedules.; Scores.; Scrapbooks.; Screenplays.; Scripts.; Set design drawings.; Sheet music.; Songs.; Speeches.; Stories.; Summaries.; Synopses.; Taxes.; Telegrams.; Television scripts.; Transcripts.; Translations.; Vouchers.; Wash drawings.; Wills.; Wood engravings.; Worksheets.; Yearbooks.; Accounts.; Address books.; Advertising.; Albums.; Articles.; Audio cassettes.; Audio tapes.; Autographs.; Awards.; Banners.; Birthday cards.; Book jackets.; Bookplates.; Budgets.; Calendars.; Caricatures.; Cartoon strips.; Cartoons.; Cashbooks.; Certificates.; Charcoal drawings.; Clippings.; Contracts.; Artists.; Authors.; Cartoonists.; Dramatists.; Foreign correspondents.; Journalists.; Women artists.; Women authors.; Women cartoonists.; Women dramatists.; Women journalists.; New York herald tribune.; World (New York, N.Y.: 1860-1931)
Access Restrictions
This collection has no restrictions.
This collection is located on-site.
Acquisition
Papers Bella Spewack Bequest of the estate of
Bequest of the estate of Bella C. Spewack, 1990.
- Series I: Cataloged Cprrespondence
  - Abbott, George (Box A)
  - Acosta, Mercedes de
  - Adams, Edie
  - Aherne, Brian
  - Albert, Eddie
  - Andrews, Julie
  - Arthur, Jean
  - Atkinson, (Justin) Brooks
  - Aumont, Jean Pierre
  - Baker, Russell
  - Baum, Vicki
  - Beaumont, Hugh (Binkie)
  - Bedford, Brian
  - Belasco, David
  - Berg, Gertrude
  - Bernstein, Aline
  - Bikel, Theodore
  - Blackmer, Sidney
  - Blatas, Arbit
  - Boag, Gil
  - Bocher, Main
  - Bonnet, Henri
  - Booth, Shirley
  - Bousquet, Marie Louise (Mrs. Jaques)
  - Boyer, Charles
  - Brook, Peter
  - Brooks, Van Wyck
  - Broun, Heywood
  - Brown, John L.
  - Brown, John Mason
  - Brown, Vanessa
  - Burford, Roger
  - Calhern, Louis
  - Carmer, Carl
  - Cerf, Bennett
  - Champion, Gower
  - Channing, Carol
  - Clavé, Antoni
  - Clooney, Rosemary
  - Clurman, Harold
  - Coca, Imogene
  - Cohen, Benjamin V.
  - Cohen, Harriet
  - Cohen, Myron
  - Colbert, Claudette
  - Collier, Constance
  - Connelly, Marc
  - Considine, Millie (Mrs. Robert)
  - Cornell, Katharine
  - Craven, Frank
  - Crawford, Cheryl
  - Crist, Judith
  - Cronkite, Walter
  - Cronyn, Hume
  - Crowther, Bosley
  - Cukor, George
  - Dalrymple, Jean (Box B)
  - Dassin, Jules
  - Davidson, Florence (Mrs. Jo)
  - Davidson, Jo
  - Day, Dorothy
  - de Mille, Clara B.
  - Douglas, Melvyn
  - Drake, Alfred
  - Duke, Vernon
  - Elath, Zehava
  - Eldridge, Florence
  - Enters, Angna
  - Erdman, Richard
  - Eudoxie, Princess (of Bulgaria)
  - Evans, Maurice
  - Ewell, Tom
  - Fadiman, Clifton
  - Ferrer, José
  - Flon, Suzanne
  - Freedley, George
  - Freud, Anna
  - Fuerholzer, T. H.
  - Garson, Greer
  - Gassner, John W.
  - Geddes, Norman Bel
  - Gershwin, Ira and Lee
  - Gershwin, Ira
  - Gielgud, John
  - Gielgud, Val
  - Gilmore, Margalo
  - Gingold, Hermione
  - Glenn, John
  - Glenville, Peter
  - Goddard, Paulette
  - Goldwyn, Samuel and Jennifer
  - Goodman, Anson Conger
  - Gordon, Max
  - Gould, Morton
  - Grimes, Tammy
  - Graham, Katharine
  - Guggenheim, Irene R.
  - Guinness, Alec
  - Guinness, Merula (Mrs. Alec)
  - Guthrie, Tyrone
  - Halliday, Richard
  - Hammerstein, Oscar
  - Harriman, William Averell
  - Harris, Jed
  - Harris, Julie
  - Harris, Rosemary
  - Harris, Sam H.
  - Harris, William, Jr
  - Hart, Lorenz
  - Hart, Moss
  - Hartl, Leon
  - Hassam, Childe
  - Hayes, Helen
  - Helburn, Theresa
  - Hellman, Lillian
  - Helpmann, Robert
  - Henri, Robert
  - Hepburn, Katharine
  - Hirsh, Jo
  - Holden, William
  - Hope, Constance
  - Hornblow, Arthur, Jr.
  - Hurok, Sol
  - Ives, Burl (Box C)
  - Jones, Barry
  - Kanin, Garson
  - Karloff, Boris
  - Kaufman, George S.
  - Keller, Helen
  - Kelly, Gene
  - Kilty, Jerome
  - King, Alan
  - King, Alexander
  - Kirk, Lisa
  - Kirkwood, James
  - Klopfer, Donald S.
  - La Follette, Clara
  - Lansbury, Edgar
  - Lawrence, Gertrude
  - Lazar, Irving P.
  - Lederer, Charles
  - Lehmann, Lilli
  - Leigh, Vivien
  - Leighton, Margaret
  - Lewis, Mary
  - Lewisohn, Irene
  - Loesser, Frank
  - Logan, Joshua
  - Lombardo, Guy
  - Luhan, Mabel Dodge
  - Lumet, Sidney
  - Lunt, Alfred
  - Lyons, Leonard and Sylvia
  - McCarey, Leo and Stella
  - MacMahon, Aline
  - Mankiewicz, Herman
  - Mantle, Burns
  - Markova, Alicia
  - Martin, Mary
  - Marx, Zeppo
  - Mellett, Lowell
  - Merivale, Jack
  - Messel, Oliver
  - Middleton, George
  - Miller, Gilbert
  - Moffo, Anna
  - Moiseivitsch, Benno
  - Montalban, Ricardo
  - Montand, Yves
  - Moore, Dudley
  - Moore, Victor
  - Morison, Patricia
  - Munsell, Patricia
  - Murray, Kathryn
  - Murrow, Edward R.
  - Nesbitt, Cathleen
  - Newmar, Julie
  - Nissen, Greta
  - Norton, Elliot
  - Nugent, Elliott
  - Oakes, Nancy
  - O'Brien, Edward J.
  - O'Casey, Sean
  - Olivier, Laurence
  - Ostrovsky, V.
  - Page, Geraldine
  - Palmer, Lilli
  - Parker, Dorothy
  - Patterson, Elizabeth
  - Pickford, Mary
  - Picon, Molly
  - Porter, Cole (Box E)
  - Powell, Dick (Box C (cont.))
  - Reid, Whitelaw
  - Reinhardt, Max
  - Reinking, Ann
  - Resnick, Regina
  - Rice, Elmer
  - Richardson, Sir Ralph
  - Richardson, Tony
  - Rios, Fernando de los
  - Ritchard, Cyril
  - Robertson, James -Justice
  - Robinson, Edward G.
  - Rodgers, Richard
  - Robson, Flora
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor
  - Rosay, Francoise
  - Ross, Frank
  - Rubin, Esther
  - Rubin, J. Robert
  - Rubin, Reuvin
  - Violet Lindsay Manners, Duchess of Rutland
  - Salmi, Albert
  - Schary, Dore (Box D)
  - Schildkraut, Joseph
  - Schmidt, Lars R.
  - Schulz, Charles M.
  - Schwartz, Arthur
  - Sellers, Peter
  - Selznick, Irene M.
  - Shaffer, Peter
  - Sherwood, Robert E.
  - Shumlin, Herman
  - Sidney, George
  - Simkovitch, Jasha
  - Simonson, Lee
  - Slezak, Walter
  - Smith, Madeline P.
  - Spewack, Bella and Sam
  - Steele, Wilbur Daniel
  - Steffens, Lincoln
  - Stokes, Rose Pastor
  - Stravinsky, Igor
  - Stromberg Jr, Hunt
  - Styne, Jule
  - Sullivan, Frank
  - Sutherland, Joan
  - Swinnerton, Frank Arthur
  - Swope, Herbert Bayard
  - Syms, Sylvia
  - Szigeti, Joseph
  - Taft, Charles P.
  - Tandy, Jessica
  - Thimmy-Reinhardt, Helene
  - Tomlin, Lily
  - Tourel, Jennie
  - Townsend, James
  - Truman, Margaret
  - Tuttle, Frank
  - Tucker, Sophie
  - Ustinov, Peter
  - Villa Lobos, Heitor
  - Wagner, Robert F.
  - Walker, Stuart
  - Wallach, Eli
  - Walters, Barbara
  - Walton, Tony
  - Wanger, Walter
  - Weaver, Fritz
  - Weeks, Constance
  - Weill, Kurt
  - Welles, Orson
  - West, Rebecca
  - Wilder, Thornton
  - Willkie, Wendell L.
  - Wilson, Julie
  - Winchell, Walter
  - Winter, Ella
  - Wood, Audrey
  - Wood, Peggy
  - Wright, Robert
  - Wyler, William
  - Wynyard, Diana
  - Zetterling, Mai
  - Zolotow, Sam
- Series II: Cataloged Manuscripts and Documents
  - Abbott, George (Box E)
  - Arthur, Jean
  - Baum, Vicki
  - Bernstein, Aline
  - Cerf, Bennett
  - Fletcher, Bramwell
  - Gershwin, Ira
  - Kern, Jerome
  - Lehmann, Lilli
  - Lindsay, Howard
  - March, Fredrick
  - Resnick, Regina
  - Spewack, Bella and Sam See Also Productions and Short Stories and Articles Series [Boxes 8-99]
    [See also Productions and Short Stories and Articles Series (Boxes]
  - Steffens, Lincoln
  - Stokes, Rose Pastor
  - Szigeti, Joseph
- Series III: Cataloged Photographs
  - Arthur, Jean
  - Baum, Vicki
  - Bergman, Ingrid
  - Bing, Rudolf
  - Blasco, Vincente Ibanez
  - Cooper, Lady Diana
  - Cornell, Katharine
  - Davidson, Jo
  - Ferrer, Jose and Hagen, Uta
  - Harriman, W.Averell
  - Hellman, Lillian
  - Kazner, Kurt
  - Martin, Mary and Preston, Robert and Spewack, Bella
  - Masaryk, Jan and Spewack, Bella
  - Shaw, George Bernard
  - Steffens, Lincoln
  - Truman, Harry S. and Spewack, Sam and Bella
  - Wilder, Thornton
  - Willkie, Wendell
- Series IV: Cataloged Art
  - Baird, Bill
  - Gard, Alex
  - Davidson, Jo
  - Hirsch, Joseph
  - Hirschfeld, Al
  - Kravchenko, Aleksei Ilich
  - L'Anglais, Pacal
  - Matorin, Mikhail Vladimirovich
  - Pavlov, Ivan Nikolaevich
  - Pusey, James Carver
  - Sotomayor, Antonio
  - Stokes, Rose Pastor
- Series V: Arranged Art
  - Buckley
  - Hambold, Ida
  - Martinez
  - O'Brien
  - Reyes
  - Silver, Joyce
  - Struglia
  - Stulberg, Tony
- Series VI: Personal Correspondence
  - Sam and Bella Letters, etc., 1920-1959, (26 folders) (Box 1)
  - Sam and Bella Letters, etc., 1960-1971, (15 folders) (Box 2)
  - Sam and Bella with family, (11 folders)
- Series VII: Friends
  - Bella's childhood friends (Sarah, Rose, Woe) (Box 3)
  - Trini Barnes
  - Jo Davidson
  - Ehle/Harris family
  - James family
  - Mary Lewis
  - Nobuko
  - Esther and Rueven Rubin
  - Julie Wilson
- Series VIII: General Correspondence
  - Includes information r.e. Tchaikovsky, Pullman Papers, Tahra Bey, Edgar Bergen, 1916-1949, (37 folders) (Box 4)
  - , 1950-1968, (19 folders) (Box 5)
  - , 1969-1981, (22 folders) (Box 6)
  - Holiday cards and postcards (Box 7)
- Series IX: Productions
  The productions are alphabetical by title. Some productions have working titles different from their actual titles: see the title list below.
  Within each production the material is in this order: correspondence (ordered chronologically by year if a lot); background information; worksheets; summaries; scripts (if more than one version, the scripts are lettered arbitrarily A-F or whatever. Some scripts are annotated.); legal (includes contracts, etc.); financial (includes box office receipts, budget information, etc. Information re royalties of many the productions are in the separate general file Financial of the collection); photographs (includes photos of rehearsals, live productions, some photos of Spewacks working with cast); playbills (in English and foreign); clippings (includes advertisements, reviews, etc.); other (song lyrics, production information,miscellaneous); printed material (includes scripts printed in magazines, scripts in book form). The scrapbooks, sheet music, and posters for each production are in separate general files, as are audio-visual materials (record albums, audio tapes, films).
  If there is not much information on a production (usually because it was never produced) then it is in one of the Miscellaneous boxes at the end of the production file. Also please note that sometimes a production was produced at different times under different titles, but one title--the most famous one--is used as a collective heading. For example, Leave it to Me is the collective heading for information about Clear All Wires and Sweeney, two earlier non-musical versions of the same basic storyline, later rewritten with Cole Porter as the musical Leave it to Me.
  The titles in bold are the actual titles or collective headings.
  - Subseries IX.1: Alphabetic List